Sex, drugs and punk rock. Add violence and time travel and you have Jubilee.
Jubilee is a comedy, drama, fantasy film directed by Derek Jarman.
Queen Elizabeth I visits late 1970s England to find a depressing
landscape where life has changed since her time.
Queen Elizabeth I / Bod, played by Jenny Runacre.
Crabs (as Little Nell), played by Nell Campbell.
Mad, played by Toyah Willcox.
Amyl Nitrite, played by Pamela Rooke.
Angel, played by Ian Charleson.
Sphinx, played by Karl Johnson.
Jubilee is a 1978 British drama film directed by Derek Jarman.
It stars Jenny Runacre, Ian Charleson, Nell Campbell,
Hermine Demoriane and a host of punk rockers.
The title refers to the Silver Jubilee of Elizabeth II in 1977.
Numerous punk icons appear in the film including Adam Ant, Toyah, Jordan (a
Malcolm McLaren protégé), Gene October and Jayne County.
It features performances by Jayne County and Adam and the Ants.
There are also cameo appearances by the Slits and Siouxsie and the Banshees.
The film was scored by Brian Eno.
The film explores themes of police brutality, street
gang, police state, group sex, dark comedy.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.